North Atlantic overview: subtropical currents and sources.
Riverine, coastal, and shipping inputs color coded for clarity.
Particles swirl clockwise, guided by the Gulf Stream and Azores flow.
Ekman and diffusion nudge fragments toward the gyre interior.
Accumulation intensifies in the Sargasso Sea monitoring box.
Beaching hotspots flare along the Carolinas and Iberian coasts.
Seasonal ramp strengthens winter convergence before easing in summer.
Validation metrics: gyre fraction rising, curvature proving non-ballistic.
Cleanup focus: high-ranked cells and persistent shore impacts.
Driftcast 2025: reproducible, judge-ready storytelling of surface plastics.